[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section 6
您好，欢迎来到第6节
of lesson 3. In this section we're going to talk a bit about
第3课的内容。在本节中，我们将讨论一些
how you can debug Lambda expressions
如何调试Lambda表达式
and streams. We look at
和溪流。我们看
how streams work. What they really do is provide us with a high level of abstraction
流如何工作。他们真正所做的是为我们提供了高水平的抽象
around the problem that we're trying to solve. Now that's
围绕我们要解决的问题。现在就是
really good from the point of view of how we watch our code,
从我们如何观察代码的角度来看，这确实非常好，
because it makes our codea lot clearer, makes the code a lot
因为它使我们的代码更加清晰，使代码很多
easier to understand. But if the code is not doing exactly what we wanted to do
更容易理解。但是，如果代码没有完全按照我们想要的去做
and we need to start debugging that code it does become
我们需要开始调试它确实变成的代码
more of an issue when we're using Lambdas and streams.
当我们使用Lambda和流时，还有更多的问题。
A lot of stuff is happening underneath the library code
库代码下发生了很多事情
that's being used by the streams API is doing a lot of work on our behalf,
流API所使用的资源代表我们做了很多工作，
which we can't see in our code. It's not easy
我们在代码中看不到这并不容易
when we want to set a breakpoint because we can only set it
当我们想设置一个断点时，因为我们只能设置它
on every coarse level in terms what streams doing.
在每个粗略的方面来讲，流在做什么。
And because of the way things happen in terms of the actual
而且由于事情发生的方式与实际情况有关
execution of the stream code where we optimize things in terms of merging
流代码的执行，我们根据合并来优化事物
operations -that type of thing- it also
操作-这种类型的东西-它也
makes it harder for us to determine what's actually happening
使我们更难确定实际发生的事情
in terms the processing. Let's look at
在处理上。让我们来看看
how we can do some simple debugging. what's happening
我们如何进行一些简单的调试。发生了什么
between methods in a stream? To do this
流中的方法之间？去做这个
we can use the peek method, which we saw a lesson 2.
我们可以使用第2课中的peek方法。
Remember that the peek method takes the input stream elements
请记住，peek方法采用输入流元素
and passes them directly to the output stream, so the output stream is
并将它们直接传递到输出流，因此输出流是
exactly the same as the input stream.
与输入流完全相同。
What it also allows us to do is to look at those elements
它也使我们能够做的是查看这些元素
as they go past. We can use something like a print statement
当他们过去时。我们可以使用类似打印声明的内容
to find out what the data that's being processed in that stream
找出该流中正在处理的数据
actually is. If we look at this example
实际上是。如果我们看这个例子
we're taking a set of words from public file,
我们从公共档案中收集了一些文字，
reading those lines
读那些线
and then we're passing that flatMap and we're using a
然后我们传递了flatMap并使用了
stream.of method call with the regular expression to split the lines
使用正则表达式调用stream.of方法以拆分行
into set of words. That stream of words is then passed into a map
成词组。然后将这些单词流传递到地图中
where we convert them to lower case. That's then passed to distinct so we can remove
我们将它们转换为小写。然后将其传递给别的，以便我们可以删除
duplicates;
复制品
that's then passed to sort. So we sort by length and finally we collect it into a list.
然后传递给排序。因此，我们按长度排序，最后将其收集到列表中。
Obviously if something is not quite working
显然，如果某件事不太有效
in terms of the way that code processes the
在代码处理方式方面
stream from our perspective we need to try and figure out what's going on.
从我们的角度来看，我们需要尝试找出正在发生的事情。
And we can use peek to do that. So we can put a
我们可以使用peek来做到这一点。所以我们可以放一个
peek call between where we read the lines
看线之间的偷看电话
and the flatMap. That way we can print out
和flatMap。这样我们就可以打印出来
the lines that are coming from the file to be checked at the lines that we're
来自文件的行要在我们正在检查的行中进行检查
seeing
看到
in the stream are the lines we expect from the file.
流中是我们希望从文件中获得的行。
if maybe a regular expression isn't working correctly
如果正则表达式无法正常工作
what we can then do is move the peek
然后我们可以做的就是移动窥视
to after the flatMap. That way we can
到flatMap之后。这样我们可以
then look at the words that are coming out from the flatMap
然后看看从flatMap出来的单词
make sure that the regular expression is processing the lines of text
确保正则表达式正在处理文本行
in the way that we want it to. You can see here that we can gradually move that
以我们想要的方式。您可以在这里看到我们可以逐步移动
peek and
偷看和
we can see different parts of the stream as
我们可以看到流的不同部分为
we're processing it. If we want to set a breakpoint,
我们正在处理它。如果要设置断点，
we can also use peek for that so that we can set a point
我们也可以使用peek来设置一个点
in the stream where we want to actually examine what's going on.
在我们想要实际检查发生了什么的流中。
In terms of
就......而言
implementing that we can actually use a null operation, so
实现我们实际上可以使用空操作，所以
something that does nothing in effect. The peek will simply pass the
没有任何作用的东西。偷看只会通过
element to the input stream directly to the output stream and
将元素直接输入到输出流并输出
do anything with them as they go past. But it allows us to set a
他们过去时，对他们做任何事情。但是它允许我们设置一个
breakpoint
断点
between the flatMap and map so, if we want to we can actually
在flatMap和map之间，因此，如果我们愿意，我们可以
user IDE and examine various things at that point.
用户IDE，然后检查各种情况。
One thing to remember is that some debugging tools don't like empty bodies, so you need
要记住的一件事是，某些调试工具不喜欢空主体，因此您需要
to
至
potentially do something there.
可能在那里做些事情。
The other thing we can do is use method reference.
我们可以做的另一件事是使用方法参考。
And rather than having the Lambda expression
而不是拥有Lambda表达式
hold all the code that we're actually executing we can kind
保留我们实际执行的所有代码，我们可以
of shift it out because what happens internally
之所以将其转移出去，是因为内部发生了什么
is that the Lambda expression is not compiled into the equivalent
是Lambda表达式未编译为等效表达式
anonymous inner class. We use the invokedynamic call
匿名内部类。我们使用invokedynamic调用
and then decide on the implementation at runtime. The drawbacks to that is obviously
然后在运行时决定实现。缺点很明显
that the
那
code that the IDE is going to look at will have an invokedynamicbytecode
IDE将要查看的代码将具有一个invokedynamicbytecode
and it makes it harder for us to actually set breakpoints.
这使我们很难实际设置断点。
Rather than doing it that way we can actually take code we've got in Lambda
与其那样做，不如说我们可以实际获取Lambda中的代码
expression
表达
and put it in a separate method. Put the method inside
并将其放在单独的方法中。把方法放进去
our class and then replace the Lambda expression
我们的课，然后替换Lambda表达式
code with the method reference to our new method.
该方法的代码引用了我们的新方法。
Having done that we can set breakpoints
完成后，我们可以设置断点
on the statements in the new method because those will be compiled normally
在新方法中的语句上，因为这些将正常编译
and we can see exactly what's going on and we can use our debugger
我们可以确切地看到发生了什么，并且可以使用调试器
to examine the program state. To summarise 6,
检查程序状态。总结一下6
debugging is harder with Lambdas and streams.
使用Lambda和流进行调试更加困难。
Because of the way that the code gets merged because of the way that there's a
由于代码合并的方式，因为存在
lot happening
发生了很多
underneath in terms of the library code it does make life harder.
就库代码而言，这确实使工作变得更加艰难。
The fact that we compile to invokedynamicbytecodes and
我们编译以调用动态字节码和
the implementations isn't decided until runtime makes life harder from the point
直到运行时使生活变得更艰难之前，才决定实现方式
of view of
的观点
breakpoints. Using peek, using method references
断点。使用窥视，使用方法参考
can simplify things and make life easier when you're trying to
可以简化事情并使生活更轻松
determine what's actually happening in your streams or Lambda code.
确定流或Lambda代码中实际发生的情况。
And that is the end of section 6.
至此第6节结束。